## **UTKARSH KESHARI**

7007310563 | utkkeshari@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/utkofficial

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Hello, my name is Utkarsh Keshari, and I am a dynamic sales professional with over 7+years of experience in sales and team management. With my strong leadership qualities and extensive experience in managing high-performing teams, I have consistently driven sales growth and exceeded revenue targets. As a skilled communicator with exceptional negotiation and problem-solving skills, I have developed and implemented successful sales strategies that have helped organizations increase their market share and achieve their business goals.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### BRILLIANT INSURANCE BROKING SERVICES PRIVATE LIMITED

OCT 2017 - OCT 2019

Team Leader

- Leading and managing a team of inside sales representatives, providing coaching, guidance, and motivation to achieve sales targets and objectives.
- Building and maintaining relationships with customers, ensuring customer satisfaction and retention, and resolving customer complaints and issues.
- Conducting regular training and development sessions for inside sales representatives, ensuring they are
  equipped with the knowledge and skills to effectively sell the companys products or services. Staying upto-date with industry trends, competitor activities, and emerging technologies, and using this knowledge to
  inform sales strategy and tactics.

### RELIANCE NIPPON LIFE INSURANCE COMPANY LIMITED

OCT 2019 - JAN 2021

Agency Recruitment and Development Manager (Sales Manager)

- Directing and coordinating all sales activities locally and regionally. Preparing sales budgets and projections and approving expenditures.
- Overseeing local and regional sales, promotions and campaigns. Planning and directing the hiring and training of new Sales Representatives.

### BYJU'S- Think & Learn Pvt. Ltd.

FEB 2021 - FEB 2022

**Business Development Associate** 

- Expected to connect with potential customers, set up meetings, counsel the students on the BYJU'S unique way of learning and assist them to become premium subscribers.
- Responsible for building strategies to enhance the company's sales and overall organizational growth.
- They conduct market research and do analysis to understand client's requirements, create business plans, generate progress reports and create presentations.

### RELEVEL BY UNACADEMY

MAR 2022 – AUG 2022

**Business Development Associate** 

- Take prospect from initial contact phase to qualified phase over the phone. Present product solutions virtually. Generate revenue by counseling prospects and converting them to sales.
- Meet and exceed pipeline contribution goals. Respond quickly to assign leads, Willingness to be measured by weekly and monthly metrics.
- Use and become an expert on the Customer Relationship Management (CRM) system.

# **Livspace Home Interior Designs E-Commerce Private Limited**

SEP 2022 - APR 2023

- Make outgoing calls to potential customers to schedule high quality leads for sales. Identify customer's needs, clarify information, research every issue, and provide solutions and/or alternatives.
- Manage a large number of outbound calls in a timely manner. Document all call information in the CRM according to standard operating procedures. Meet personal/team qualitative and quantitative targets.
- Schedule Experience Centre visits with our design team as per defined process. Follow-up with internal stakeholders to ensure that appropriate action has been taken on customer requests and complaints. Make reminder calls to customers & schedule appointments, ensuring that the calls happen as per scheduled time.

# Physics Wallah Pvt. Ltd.

APR 2023 - APR 2024

Senior Associate

- Initiate outbound calls to potential leads from a designated target audience.
- Conduct thorough needs assessments to understand the requirements and preferences of prospective students.
- Recommend appropriate courses from our portfolio that aligns with the learner's goals and objectives.
- Develop and maintain strong relationships with potential learners through regular follow-ups and personalized interactions.
- Nurture leads through ongoing communication and engagement to facilitate future conversions.

# **EDUCATION**

College: J.S. University 2020

Course: Masters of Business Administration, College: Mahatma Gandhi Kashi Vidhyapeeth

idhi Kashi Vidhyapeeth 2018

Course: Bachelor of Commerce

## **SKILLS & OTHER**

PythonOSPF

Excel • Data Science

• CCNA • SEO

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

- CCC (Course of Computer Concept) from NIELIT
- CCNA from Network Kings
- Digital Marketing from Google
- Excel from Great Learning

### **ACHIEVEMENTS & AWARDS**

- JAVASCRIPT
- PROJECT MANAGEMENT
- WEB ANALYTICS